https://www.cheesemans.com/privacy-policy

Cheesemans' Ecology Safaris
Privacy Policy
Updated June 3, 2020, Version 2.1Cheesemans’ Ecology Safaris values and respects our travelers above all and takes their privacy very seriously. Information Collected and How We Use ItFor logistical and permitting purposes, we collect personal information as part of our reservation process (information can include email, name, passport number, medical status, date of birth, etc). When you provide us with personal information, we will not sell, license, transmit or disclose this information outside of Cheesemans’ Ecology Safaris unless (1) you expressly authorize us to do so, (2) it is necessary to allow our service providers, representatives, or agents to provide services to us or to you related to your travel reservation, (3) governments require or we exercise our discretion to provide information for immigration, border control, anti-terrorism, or any other security purpose, or (4) we are required or permitted by law.When you make a reservation with us, you are opting to receive communications about your specific travel through email, postal mail, or other appropriate method. You can manage some of your messaging preferences through your account settings, but note that you cannot opt out of receiving certain administrative, transactional, or legal messages from Cheesemans’ Ecology Safaris.We never share or sell your information with third parties for promotional purposes.We only communicate with your emergency contact with permission from you or in the event of an emergency or other situation that we determine is serious.Data RetentionWe retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements).When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize personal information. If this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.We will retain information we process on behalf of our customers as a data processor for as long as needed to provide services to our customers (unless deletion is requested at an earlier time by the customer) and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.Security StatementWe have taken all reasonable steps and implemented appropriate security measures to protect your personal information.Email and Direct MarketingWe use email as our fundamental and most efficient method of communication with you about your travel and reservation. However, you have the option of specifying your preferred method of communication with you.We also use email to distribute our newsletter, to notify you of upcoming safaris and other information that may interest you, and to answer your request for specific safari information. You can opt-out of receiving these promotional emails at any time.We may from time to time send you information about our services via the postal service. You can opt-out of receiving these promotional mailers as well.You have the right to ask, in writing, not to receive direct marketing material from us. If available, you can amend your previous preference on our website(s), use our “unsubscribe newsletter form,” or refer to other literature containing unsubscribe instructions. Once properly notified by you, we will take steps to stop using your information in the specified manner. Please allow us a reasonable period of time in order to satisfy your request.Internet Privacy and CookiesWe may use interest-based advertising from Google, Facebook, and other providers that collect data from you. Data collected can include, but are not limited to, your Internet domain, website pages you visit, your browser type, operating system, date and time and length of your visit.If you don’t want your data collected with Google Analytics on all Internet webpages, you can install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser add-on for each browser (for example, Internet Explorer, Safari, Firefox, Chrome, etc.). Search the web for “Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on” to download this app. Be aware that there are also other search engines and advertising methods that collect data, and this app only works for Google Analytics.When we use Internet advertising and remarketing we may use cookies to enhance and individualize your experience or to store user identification. If you do not want to have cookies stored on your computer, you can disable them in your browser settings.We may also use web beacons and other methodologies that identify when a webpage is opened.Our Internet marketing strategies never associate personally identifiable information with remarketing lists, cookies, data feeds, or other anonymous identifiers.Please note that we may provide links to other related websites that have privacy policies not consistent with ours.Information we collect while advertising on the Internet or elsewhere will never be shared with third parties.Using our services from outside the United StatesIf you visit our website or give us your information from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be processed in the United States or other countries where the laws might differ from those in your country. Please be assured that we take steps to protect your information and abide by the European Union’s (EU) General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), effective May 25, 2018.ContactYou may contact us online concerning our Privacy Policy, or write to us at the following address:Cheesemans’ Ecology Safaris555 N Santa Cruz AvenueLos Gatos, California 95030Changes to this Privacy PolicyWe may change this Policy at any time and from time to time without notice. The most recent version of the Policy is reflected by the revision date located at the top of this Policy.
